Guide to the Greater New Haven Coalition for People Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Greater New Haven Coalition for People records
1981-2014
MS 2007
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
12.25
(23 boxes)
The collection comprises records of the Greater New Haven Coalition for People, a grassroots organization that advocates for lower and middle income residents of New Haven, Connecticut. Materials include correspondence, financial and fundraising records, files on topics and events that the Coalition worked on, and posters and protest signs. Materials date from 1981 to 2014. Much of the collection concerns different issues the Coalition focused on, including the removal of bus stops from the City of New Haven, medical care for the low-income and uninsured in the local hospitals, conditions of public housing, and programs like the West Rock Youth Leadership Program and Tenants Against Drugs Dammit!
Greater New Haven Coalition for People
Arrangement
The records are arranged into the following series: I: Correspondence, 1992-2009. II: Financial and fundraising records, 1983-2011. III. Meeting agendas and minutes, 1988-2014. IV: Topical files, 1981-2010. V: Posters and protest signs, 1986-1990.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The collection comprises records of the Greater New Haven Coalition for People, a grassroots organization that advocates for lower and middle income residents of New Haven, Connecticut. Materials include correspondence, financial and fundraising records, files on topics and events that the Coalition worked on, and posters and protest signs. Materials date from 1981 to 2014. Much of the collection concerns different issues the Coalition focused on, including the removal of bus stops from the City of New Haven, medical care for the low-income and uninsured in the local hospitals, conditions of public housing, and programs like the West Rock Youth Leadership Program and Tenants Against Drugs Dammit!
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Greater New Haven Coalition for People, 2014.
Biographical / Historical
The Greater New Haven Coalition for People was founded in 1981 as an umbrella group of different community agencies and organizations that were concerned about the effect of budget cuts on programs in the city of New Haven, Connecticut. Soon it evolved into a grassroots organization run by a board of directors and work mainly undertaken by volunteers and some paid organizers that focused on organizing local residents. Coalition for People addresses a variety of issues that impact the low and middle income residents of New Haven, including conditions and safety of public housing, health care, public transit safety and availability, and programs for children and adolescents.
Community activists; Local transit; Medical care; Medically uninsured persons; Political activists; Public housing; New Haven (Conn.); Greater New Haven Coalition for People
- Correspondence, 1992-2009; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  Series I comprises general correspondence sent by and to the Coalition for People. The major topics include the Coalition's financial difficulties in the 1990s, donations sent to the Coalition, and the resignation of a board member.
  - General
    - 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 2009 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Robin Latta Tweedy's letter, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Financial and fundraising records, 1983-2011; Series II
  Series II contains annual and other financial reports, solicitation letters, grant descriptions and applications, and state and federal tax filings.
  - Accounting- contractual audit, 1993 (Box 1a, Folder 1)
  - Annual reports
    - 1993-1999 (Box 1a, Folder 2)
    - 1994-2011 (Box 1a, Folder 3)
    - 1997 (Box 1a, Folder 4)
    - 1998 (Box 1a, Folder 5)
    - 2000 (Box 1a, Folder 6)
    - 2001 (Box 1a, Folder 7)
    - 2003 (Box 1a, Folder 8)
    - 2003-2004 (Box 1a, Folder 9)
    - 2013 (Box 1a, Folder 10)
  - Financial reports
    - 1983-1986 (Box 1a, Folder 11)
    - 1991 (Box 1a, Folder 12)
    - 1993-1994 (Box 1a, Folder 13)
    - 1994 (Box 1a, Folder 14)
    - 1995 (Box 1a, Folder 15)
    - 1995-2004 (Box 1a, Folder 16)
    - 1996 (Box 1a, Folder 17)
    - 2013 (Box 1a, Folder 18)
    - IRS reports, 2012 (Box 1a, Folder 19)
    - Supplementary materials, 2012 (Box 1a, Folder 20)
  - Fundraising records
    - Fundraising letters, 1996, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Fundraising letters and descriptions, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Grants- general
      - 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Grants- information, guidelines, letters, etc., 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Grant proposals, 1996-2002 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Grantor lists
      - 1993-2002 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - 1996-2002 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Grants, pending, 2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Ben and Jerry's Foundation
      - 1991 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - 1992 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - 1993 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - 2002 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Campaign for Human Development- local, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Campaign for Human Development- national, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Carolyn Foundation, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - City Missionary Association, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Community Training and Assistance, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Comprehensive Grant Program- annual statement submission, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Comprehensive Grant Program public hearing, 1993 February 18 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Discount Foundation, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Fairfield County non-profit loan fund, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Funding committee, 1997, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Funding committee reports, 1997-2003 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Funding Exchange, 1996-1999 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Haymarket's People Fund
      - 1985-1991 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - 1991 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - 1993 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - 1994 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - 1994-2002 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - 2002-2003 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Marianist Sharing Fund, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Mott small grants, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - New Haven Foundation
      - 1992 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - 1993 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - RESIST, 2003, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - United Church of Christ, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - United Church on the Green, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Tax records
    - Connecticut corporation taxes, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Connecticut sales tax, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Connecticut state taxes- withholding, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Connecticut tax regulations, 1997-2005 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Federal tax exempt letter, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Federal withholding tax, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Federal unemployment tax, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Form 990 tax filings
      - 1986 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - 1989 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - 1991 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - 1993 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - 1994 (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - 1995 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - 1996 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - 1997 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - 1998 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - 1999 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - 2000 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - 2001 (Box 5, Folder 19)
      - 2002 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - 2003 (Box 5, Folder 21)
      - 2004 (Box 5, Folder 22-23)
      - 2006 (Box 5, Folder 24)
      - 2007 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - 2008 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - 2010 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Income tax returns, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - IRS and Social Security Administration, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Public charities
      - 1995 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Public charities- tax information, 2004-2010 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Tax returns, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Meeting agendas and minutes, 1988-2014; Series III
  Series III contains agendas and minutes from monthly meetings, annual meetings, board meetings, and conventions. Monthly meetings focused on the financial status of Coalition for People and projects that were in progess. Annual meetings focused on projects in progress, organization structure review and work towards new projects. Board meetings focused on the budget and direction of projects for Coalition for People. Conventions focused on action sessions for such interest areas as youth empowerment, public housing issues and health care. Conventions also provided resources for the New Haven community in the same interest areas.
  - General
    - 1994 (Box 6a, Folder 1)
    - 1995 (Box 6a, Folder 2)
    - 1996 (Box 6a, Folder 3)
    - 1997 (Box 6a, Folder 4)
    - 1997-2003 (Box 6a, Folder 5)
    - 1998 (Box 6a, Folder 6)
    - 1999-2000 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 2001 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - 2002 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - 2003 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - 2004 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - 2005 (Box 7, Folder 6-7)
    - 2006 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - 2007 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - 2008 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - 2009 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - 2010 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - 2011 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - 2012 January (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - 2012 February (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - 2012 May (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - 2012 June (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - 2012 July (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - 2012 September (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - 2012 October (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - 2012 November (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - 2012 December (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - 2013 January (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - 2013 March (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - 2013 April (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - 2013 July (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - 2013 September (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - 2013 October (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - 2013 November (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Re-envisioning task force, 1988-1990 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Annual meetings
    - 1993 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - 2000 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - 2001 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - 2002 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - 2004 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - 2010- Speaker (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - 2012- Attendance (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - 2012- Work (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - 2013 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - 2014 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Board of directors, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Board- retreat, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Conventions
    - 1993 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - 1994 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Attendees, 1991-1994 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Topical files, 1981-2010; Series IV
  Topical files cover a diverse range of subjects of interest to Coalition for People and events Coalition for People held and/or participated in. Also included with the topical files are materials related to three different major projects undertaken by the Coalition. These include stopping, then reversing the removal of bus stops by the City of New Haven after the city's agreement with the Omni Hotel; health care and health insurance initiatives to help lower income residents of New Haven; and the West Rock Youth Leadership Program, a summer program which provided children of that neighborhood classes, mentorships, and recreational opportunities.
  - General
    - 1981 (Box 9a, Folder 1)
    - 1982-1990 (Box 9a, Folder 2)
    - 1987-1994 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - 1993 (Box 10, Folder 2-3)
    - 1996 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - 1997 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - 1998 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - 1999 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - 2003 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Undated (Box 10, Folder 9-10)
    - Activities, 1995-2002 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Advertisers and donors, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Advertising books, 1987-1989 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Applicants, 1998, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Assorted campaigns, Undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Board
      - 1994-2002 (Box 10, Folder 16)
      - Undated (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Bus safety, 2009-2010 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - By-laws, 1992-1999 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Certificates, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Coalition contact lists, Undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Early description of Coalition for People, 1997, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Facts, miscellaneous, Undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Facts and figures regarding anything and everything, 1997, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Film- Capitalism, 2009 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Film- Norma Rae, 2007 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Film- Salt of the Earth, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Film- Sicko, 2007 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Fliers, Undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - History, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - History and definitions, 1995, undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - History/mission, 1989-1994 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Housing
      - 1994 (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - Undated (Box 11, Folder 15-16)
    - Housing Authority of the City of New Haven, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Housing petitions, undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Infrastructure, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Interviews, Undated (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Job applications, 2003 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Labels, Undated (Box 11, Folder 22-23)
    - Letterhead, Undated (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Lobbying, Undated (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Mailings, 1998, undated (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Master list- churches, Undated (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Members
      - 1994-2002 (Box 11, Folder 28)
      - 2003, undated (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Memories of beloved members, Undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - News, 1991-2002 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - News articles
      - 2011 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - 2013 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - News articles and general information, 2009 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - News articles from journals, 2011 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Organizing
      - 2004 (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - Undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Religious coalition, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Media resources for Coalition for People, Undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Staff and volunteers, 1994-2003 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Staff reports, 2006 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Stevens/St. Johns surveys, Undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Training, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Training- programs and curriculums, 1994-2001, undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Transportation
      - 2004-2009, undated (Box 12, Folder 16)
      - 2005 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Weekly Controller, Undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Workshops, 1993-1998 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Yale Divinity School, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Bus stop closures
    - 1997-2003 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - 1999-circa 2005 (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
    - 2007 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Aldermanic resolution, 2004 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Code, 1993, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Fliers, 2000-2005 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Fliers and articles, 1996-2003 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence
      - 1997-1999 (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - 1997-2006 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - My ride, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - News clippings
      - 1997-2003 (Box 13, Folder 11)
      - 2004-2008 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Petitions
      - Circa 1996-circa 2004 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - Circa 1996, 1998-2000 (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - Circa 1996, 1998-2007 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Protest group, 1997-2002 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Transportation, 1998-2004 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Health care
    - 1993-1998 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - 1993-2007 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - 1994-2003 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - 1994-2005 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - 1995-2003 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - 1995-2005 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Health action project, 1995-2002 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Aging survey, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Articles and fliers, 1994-2003 (Box 15, Folder 6-7)
    - Center for Medicare Advocacy, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Drug assistance, 2000-2001 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Fax to President Obama regarding single payer, 2009 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Free care, 1994-1996 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Health care action project meetings, 1994-2001 (Box 16, Folder 2-3)
    - Health care for all, 1996-2003 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Third district health care for all, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Health care for uninsured, 1989-1997 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Health fair- NAACP, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - HMOs, 1994-1999 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Health Security Act, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Home care, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Hospital of Saint Raphael, 1976-2002 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Hospital of Saint Raphael and Yale-New Haven Hospital, Undated (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Legislation, 1995-2010 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Managed care- HMOs, 1994-2000 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Medicaid, 1995-2000 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Medicare, 1995-2004 (Box 17, Folder 3-4)
    - Petitions, Undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Petitions- signed, Undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Pharmaceuticals, 2002-2004 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Press conference, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Real Clout, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Senior citizens, 2002, undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Single payer (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - 1993-2003 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - 1993-2009 (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - 1997-2009 (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - 2001, undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - 2009-2010 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Social security, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Surveys, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - United Seniors in Action, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Yale-New Haven Hospital
      - General, 1993-1997 (Box 18, Folder 9-10)
      - Beds, 1993-1996 (Box 18, Folder 11)
      - Complaints, 1993-1998 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - West Rock Youth Leadership Program
    - General, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 1-3)
    - Attendance, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Community event, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Consent and application forms, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - House rules, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Participant list, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Placements, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Proposal, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Work with other coalitions and organizations
    - Central Labor Council by-laws, Undated (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Community Foundation New Haven, 1996 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Community Resource Committee, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Community Works of Connecticut
      - 1996-2000 (Box 19, Folder 14)
      - 1998 (Box 19, Folder 15)
      - 1999-2003 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Grassroots Community Labor Forum, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - United Way, 1995 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - UCAN training for staff- notes, Circa 1990 (Box 19, Folder 19)
- Posters and protest signs, 1986-1990; Series V
  Series V comprises posters and protest signs for various projects and causes. They are related to bus stop removal, conditions in public housing, and Tenants Against Drugs Dammit! (TADD). There are also posters with photographs from events and conventions held by the Coalition.
  - General, Undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Bus stop removal, Undated (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Housing conditions, 1986, undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Posters with pictures of events, 1988-1990, undated (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Tenants Against Drugs Dammit!, Undated (Box 20, Folder 5)